Guide to the Doris Duke Photograph Collection, 1870-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Shangri La, 1925-1960
  - Series of Black and white photographs and negatives from photo shoot of Doris Duke, James Cromwell and Kahanamoku brothers at Shangri La. Select photos appeared in Life Magazine, 1939 Mar 20. Oversize of select photos stored separately in Box 68. (Box 63, Folder PHSL001)
  - Series of black and white glass plate negatives from photo shoot of Doris Duke, James Cromwell, Sam Kahanamoku, and construction of Shangri La. Several of the negatives are different than the photographs and negatives in Box 63. (Box 64, Folder PHSL001)
  - Black and white photographs and negatives of staff at Shangri La. Some images may be pre-Shangri La as they include images of stone camel, 1939-1940 (Box 63, Folder PHSL002)
  - Black and white photographs of scenic area surrounding Shangri La. Includes photos of pets, water, men cleaning pool, and some exterior shots of the main residence, 1939-1941 (Box 63, Folder PHSL003)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke, James Cromwell, and Kahanamoku brothers and family. Photos document trip to the Big Island, 1937-1939 (Box 63, Folder PHSL004)
  - Black and white photographs of scenery from trips around Oahu with friends and James Cromwell, 1937-1938 (Box 63, Folder PHSL005)
  - Black and white photographs of interior and exterior of caretaker's cottage at Shangri La, circa 1940 (Box 63, Folder PHSL006)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La, interior and exterior. Rooms include dining room and Playhouse, 1939-1940 (Box 63, Folder PHSL007)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La, all exteriors. Includes images of facade of main residence, pool, Playhouse, and master bedroom, circa 1941 (Box 63, Folder PHSL008)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke with Kahanamoku brothers and friends. Images also include Johnny Gomez and James Cromwell. Many of the photos taken during Doris Duke's honeymoon and prior to the completion of Shangri La. Includes photographs, negatives, and duplicate photographs (not a complete set), 1937-1938 (1 of 2) (Box 63, Folder PHSL009)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke with Kahanamoku brothers and friends. Images also include Johnny Gomez and James Cromwell. Many of the photos taken during Doris Duke's honeymoon and prior to the completion of Shangri La. Includes photographs, negatives, and duplicate photographs (not a complete set), 1937-1938 (2 of 2) (Box 63, Folder PHSL009)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke and crew sailing off Waikiki, 1937-1941 (Box 65, Folder PHSL010)
  - Black and white photographs of Anna Furtado Kahanamoku and Sarge Kahanmoku at Shangri La, 1941 (Box 65, Folder PHSL011)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke's cruiser, Kailani LahiLahi, in Hawaii, during repairs and then ready to sail. Also includes 1 photo of Kimo with its new cover, circa 1938 (Box 65, Folder PHSL012)
  - Black and white photographs of construction phases of Shangri La. Also includes view of Doris Duke's property and where it ends and becomes Helen Strong Carter's. View is from the ocean, 1937 (Box 65, Folder PHSL013)
  - Variety of Black and white photographs of Hawaii's scenic views. Majority of photos are stamped with a note for permission by the War Dept (a-m). Scenes include coastlines, volcanoes, waterfalls, and blowholes. Photos are commercial shots, 1925-1935 (Box 65, Folder PHSL014)
  - Series of Black and white photographs documenting Doris Duke's life in Hawaii. Photos include interior and exterior shots of Shangri La, scenic shots of surrounding area, and Miss Duke with friends. Film actress, Loretta Young, may be one of Miss Duke's guests, 1940-1941 (Box 65, Folder PHSL015)
  - Black and white photographs of young man and woman near wall by Shangri La pool. The woman smoking cigarette may be Loretta Young, film actress. Young man may be son of Alec Cunningham-Reid. Includes negatives, 1939-1941 (Box 65, Folder PHSL016)
  - Series of Black and white photographs depicting mainly exterior shots of Shangri La. Folder also includes shots of gardens, facades, pool, sheep crossing road, and several interior shots, 1941 (Box 65, Folder PHSL017)
  - Series of color photos of interior of Damascus room which was completed in 1955. Unidentified man appear in 4 shots. Includes color negatives, 1957 (Box 65, Folder PHSL018)
  - Series of Black and white photographs depicting interior of Shangri La after Hearst sale [post 1941]. Included are a few views looking out from Shangri La, circa 1941 (Box 65, Folder PHSL019)
  - Series of Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors. Photos depict sun-bathing pavilion, Mughal garden, and other scenes, 1942 (Box 65, Folder PHSL020)
  - Six Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors, parrots, and couch and tapestry. Notes written on back of photos, possibly written by Doris Duke, circa 1940 (Box 65, Folder PHSL021)
  - Series of color photographs, faded and blurred, depicting exterior scenes of Shangri La and people, including Johnny Gomez. Folder includes photos of an unidentified woman with parrot, gardens, and a view of Shangri La across the water from Diamond Head area. Photos also include shots of another residence, possibly Rubirosa's house in Argentina, 1948-1950 (Box 65, Folder PHSL022)
  - Black and white photographs of two German Shepherds at pool and a chandelier. Photos removed from paper album, 1940-1945 (Box 65, Folder PHSL023)
  - Color photos of interior the Turkish Room and the hallway between Doris Duke's bedroom and the central hallway at Shangri La. Handwritten notes on the back of three photos reads, "Rec'd from Okura 4/28/81", 1981 (Box 65, Folder PHSL024)
  - Color photos of playhouse chandelier, circa 1950 (Box 65, Folder PHSL025)
  - Series of Black and white photographs documenting early construction work of Shangri La. Photos show blasting in yacht basin and excavation for water main. Each photo has a typed date/explanation, 1937 (Box 65, Folder PHSL026)
  - Series of six Black and white photographs depicting interior patio shots at Shangri La, 1942 (Box 65, Folder PHSL027)
  - Black and white photographs of Johnny Gomez on motor scooter, 1938-1945 (Box 65, Folder PHSL028)
  - Series of Black and white photographs documenting the early stages of construction of Shangri La and the arrival of Doris Duke's motorboat, Kimo. Other shots include the farmer's road nursery and Doris Duke Cromwell's arrival by a Pan Am Clipper, 1937 (1 of 3) (Box 66, Folder PHSL029)
  - Series of Black and white photographs documenting the early stages of construction of Shangri La and the arrival of Doris Duke's motorboat, Kimo. Other shots include the farmer's road nursery and Doris Duke Cromwell's arrival by a Pan Am Clipper, 1937 (2 of 3) (Box 66, Folder PHSL029)
  - Series of Black and white photographs documenting the early stages of construction of Shangri La and the arrival of Doris Duke's motorboat, Kimo. Other shots include the farmer's road nursery and Doris Duke Cromwell's arrival by a Pan Am Clipper, 1937 (3 of 3) (Box 66, Folder PHSL029)
  - Black and white photographs of Johnny Gomez having fun at Shangri La, circa 1937 (Box 67, Folder PHSL030)
  - Selection of Black and white photographs documenting Doris Duke's patio tile commission in Isfahan for Shangri La. A. Rabenou is pictured in 3 shots, 1938-1939 (Box 67, Folder PHSL031)
  - Black and white photographs of Varamin mihrab with handwritten notes on the back reading, "American Institute for Iranian Art and Archaeology." The color photos are close ups of the mihrab installed at Shangri La in 1976. Includes installation sketches by Johnny Gomez, undated, 1976 (Box 68, Folder PHSL032)
  - Series of Black and white photographs documenting Doris Duke's trip to Kauai, HI, 1935-1939 (Box 67, Folder PHSL033)
  - Group portrait of guests at Hawaiian luau at the Brays in Honolulu. Seated in back are Johnny Gomez, Priscilla and Angier Duke, Doris Duke, and Sam Kahanamoku, 1937 (Box 67, Folder PHSL034)
  - Series of color photos, created from slides, of interior and exterior views of Shangri La, scenery of Diamond Head, and several shots of guests enjoying the house. People include Johnny Gomez and Sarge Kahanamoku, 1945-1950 (Box 67, Folder PHSL035)
  - Black and white photograph of Doris Duke and Johnny Gomez, sitting with dog, 1936-1939 (Box 67, Folder PHSL036)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke and James Cromwell, dressed in Hawaiian shirts and leis. Also includes two shots of James Cromwell riding in a boat with Sam Kahanamoku, 1936-1937 (Box 67, Folder PHSL037)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke and friends taking boat ride. Boat ride most likely documents Miss Duke's pickup by her friends after arrival by ship to Hawaiian islands, 1936-1939 (Box 67, Folder PHSL038)
  - Series of Black and white photographs of decorative panels at Shangri La. Handwritten notes reverse sides, circa 1949 (Box 67, Folder PHSL039)
  - Black and white photograph of Shangri La from ocean, circa 1941 (Box 68, Folder PHSL040)
  - View of Shangri La from above during construction. View focuses on building on Playhouse, 1938 Nov 1 (Box 67, Folder PHSL041)
  - Black and white photographs of designs for fountain in Shangri La patio (never installed in SL, but in Palm Room, Duke Farms). Included in folder are two separate designs with dealers, 1938-1939 (Box 67, Folder PHSL042)
  - Exterior views of Shangri La. Photos show exterior of main structure, Miss Duke's bedroom, and garage under caretaker's cottage, 1939-1940 (Box 67, Folder PHSL043)
  - Series of Black and white photographs documenting wedding reception of Bernice Kahanamoku and Gilbert Lee. Doris Duke served as her matron of honor. Duke Kahanamoku served at best man. Wedding date was Aug. 24, 1940. Reception held at Kona Inn in Kailua-Kona, big island of Hawaii, 1940 (Box 67, Folder PHSL044)
  - Black and white photographs depicting more detailed views of the interior and exterior of Shangri La. Photos offer closeups of craftsmanship and fine handiwork. Select photos have handwriting on reverse. Includes shot of Moon Garden and Miss Duke's bathroom, 1939-1940 (Box 67, Folder PHSL045)
  - Series of negatives documenting the interior and exterior of Shangri La. Negatives are of images in PHSL017. Negatives show the various rooms like dining room and Miss Duke's bedroom as well as different views of the playhouse and other scenic shots, 1939-1940 (Box 67, Folder PHSL046)
  - Negative of photo of Doris Duke shopping for mother of pearl dressers at Damascus bazaar for Shangri La, 1938 (Box 67, Folder PHSL047)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke and James Cromwell with the basketball team that they sponsored, "Cromwell Hawaiians", 1937-1938 (Box 68, Folder PHSL048)
  - Photos sent to Marian Paschal from unidentified person. Images include orchids, ancient statues, and reliefs. Several images have handwritten descriptions on reverse, undated (Box 67, Folder PHSL049)
  - Black and white photographs of various interior and exterior shots at Shangri La, circa 1945 (1 of 2) (Box 67, Folder PHSL051)
  - Black and white photographs of various interior and exterior shots at Shangri La, circa 1945 (2 of 2) (Box 67, Folder PHSL051)
  - Print or sketch of David Kahanamoku entitled "David." Print is of a pencil drawing of David's profile, 1935 (Box 67, Folder PHSL052)
  - Black and white photographs of Sam Kahanamoku, wearing shorts, working outside and playing small guitar at Shangri La, 1939-1940 (Box 67, Folder PHSL053)
  - Group portrait of guests at Hawaiian luau at the Brays in Honolulu. Marian Pascal is standing fifth from the left, 1935 (Box 67, Folder PHSL055)
  - Group of professional news photographs taken in Hawaii. One photo includes three Kahanamoku brothers. Photo of house is possibly the Hayward residence or Alsop House. Oversize of house photo stored separately in Box 68, 1935-1940 (Box 67, Folder PHSL056)
  - Black and white photographs of Doris Duke and Marian Paschal at United Chinese Relief Society party, 1941 (Box 67, Folder PHSL057)
  - Group photo of (L to R) Sam Kahanamoku, James Cromwell, and unidentified man sitting on beach, 1935-1939 (Box 67, Folder PHSL058)
  - Black and white photograph of five men canoeing. Johnny Gomez is seated first in canoe. Other men may include members of the Kahanamoku family, 1935-1940 (Box 69, Folder PHSL059)
  - Black and white photograph of Doris Duke and James Cromwell sitting at a table. Doris is speaking to a woman, possibly a waitress, and holding a newspaper, 1935-1939 (Box 69, Folder PHSL060)
  - Group portrait of (L to R) unidentified man, Marian Paschal, and Sarge Kahanamoku, 1935-1940 (Box 69, Folder PHSL061)
  - Selection of color slides relating to Shangri La and Honolulu, 1960 (Box 69, Folder PHSL062)
  - Selection of color slides documenting exterior landscape of Shangri La. Slides include people such as Joey Castro and Johnny Gomez. Related to photographs in PHSL083, circa 1950s (Box 69, Folder PHSL063)
  - Selection of color slides documenting activities as Shangri La. Includes shots of Joey Castro, circa 1950s (Box 69, Folder PHSL064)
  - Color photos enclosed in a letter to "Dorshka" from Albert Kornfeld. Photos are of people and scenes at Shangri La, 1957 (Box 69, Folder PHSL065)
  - Group portrait of guests at a Hawaiian luau at the Brays in Honolulu. Marian Paschal can be seen standing, third from right. Also, young woman crouched behind other guests towards the left is most likely Doris Duke, 1935 (Box 68, Folder PHSL066)
  - Group portraits of Marion Wyeth Sims and others, 1937 (Box 68, Folder PHSL067)
  - Selection of Black and white photographs documenting progress at Shangri La. Includes shots of monkey cages and aviary, 1938-1940 (Box 69, Folder PHSL068)
  - Color slides and Black and white postcards of Anna Kennesay's wedding party. Doris Duke was maid of honor. Others in wedding party are unidentified. Duke Kahanamoku may be one of the guests and in a few of the images, 1958 (Box 69, Folder PHSL069)
  - Black and white photographs featuring James Cromwell and others onsite during the construction phase of Shangri La. File also includes photos of boat, Kailani Lahilahi, 1937-1938 (Box 69, Folder PHSL070)
  - Black and white photograph of Doris Duke with one of her dogs, standing in the Playhouse, with the pool in the background, 1960-1965 (Box 68, Folder PHSL071)
  - Color photograph of stained glass window, formerly on loan to the Duke University Museum of Art. Transferred to Shangri La, Turkish Room, in 1988. Included in file is letter from Registrar at Museum to Susan Fisher, Secretary to Doris Duke, 1988 (Box 69, Folder PHSL072)
  - Color photos of the Turkish Room, 1982 (Box 69, Folder PHSL074)
  - Watercolor proposal of Living Room at Shangri La. View is of the section looking east, 1937 (Box 69, Folder PHSL075)
  - Black and white photograph of cascading fountain at Shangri La, 1940-1941 (Box 69, Folder PHSL076)
  - Black and white photographs of friends at Shangri La and on boat. Includes photo of Alec Cunningham-Reid's two sons, Michael and Noel. Also includes some negatives, circa 1941 (Box 69, Folder PHSL077)
  - Color Polaroids, silver setting on dining room table, including silver Swan, at Shangri La, circa 1971 (Box 69, Folder PHSL078)
  - Color photographs of various views of Shangri La, interior and exterior, 1989 (Box 69, Folder PHSL079)
  - Color photographs, Turkish Room, Shangri La. Handwritten notes and numbers written on backs of photos, 1981 (Box 69, Folder PHSL080)
  - Various photographs of Joey Castro, Art Simmons, and two unidentified people at Shangri La and in Hawaii, 1960-1965 (Box 69, Folder PHSL083)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La, golfing in Hawaii, and friends, circa 1941 (Box 69, Folder PHSL084)
  - Color glass mounted slides of Hawaii, Molokai, circa 1930s (1 of 2) (Box 70, Folder PHSL085)
  - Color glass mounted slides of Hawaii, Molokai, circa 1930s (2 of 2) (Box 70, Folder PHSL085)
  - Color glass mounted slides of Doris Duke and James Cromwell with basketball team they sponsored (see SL048), 1937-1938 (Box 70, Folder PHSL086)
  - Color slides of Shangri La, Hawaii, 1937-1940 (1 of 3) (Box 70, Folder PHSL087)
  - Color slides of Shangri La, Hawaii, 1937-1940 (2 of 3) (Box 70, Folder PHSL087)
  - Color slides of Shangri La, Hawaii, 1937-1940 (3 of 3) (Box 70, Folder PHSL087)
  - Color and black and white photographs of Shangri La, Hawaii, 1940s-1960s, 1988 (Box 70, Folder PHSL088)
  - Photographs of the Playhouse ceiling and hala tree, 1973 Oct 2 (Box 70, Folder PHSL089)
  - Color photographs of interior and exterior of Shangri La. Includes images of repairs that need to be done, circa 1970s (Box 70, Folder PHSL090)
  - Photograph of Pele, a volcano in Hawaii, 1984 Mar (Box 70, Folder PHSL091)
  - Color photographs of furniture and clothing inventory at Shangri La, circa 1980s (1 of 2) (Box 70, Folder PHSL092)
  - Color photographs of furniture and clothing inventory at Shangri La, circa 1980s 2 of 2) (Box 71, Folder PHSL092)
  - Photographs of Shangri La. Includes exterior, fence and interior details, circa 1990s (Box 71, Folder PHSL093)
  - Photograph of Cliff Walk at Shangri La. Includes note on the back of the photograph, undated (Box 71, Folder PHSL094)
  - Negatives of Shangri La and other locations on Hawaii. Some shots include Doris Duke, undated (Box 71, Folder PHSL095)
  - Black and white photographs of Playhouse at Shangri La. Photograph by Henry Inn, circa 1941 (Box 72, Folder PHSL096)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors by Horst (Conde Nast), 1957 (1 of 3) (Box 72, Folder PHSL097)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors by Horst (Conde Nast), 1957 (1 of 3) (Box 72, Folder PHSL097)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors by Horst (Conde Nast), 1957 (1 of 3) (Box 72, Folder PHSL097)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors Henry Inn, 1957 (1 of 2) (Box 72, Folder PHSL098)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors Henry Inn, 1957 (2 of 2) (Box 72, Folder PHSL098)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors, 1957 (Box 72, Folder PHSL099)
  - Shangri La Aerial photos, 1953-1957 (Opaperfolder PHSL100)
  - Photograph of Johnny Gomez in mid-dive. Signed "Aloha Nui, Johnny Gomez", 1927 (Box 68, Folder PHSL101)
  - Black and white photographs of Shangri La exteriors by Horst (Conde Nast), 1957. Photographs are damaged. (Box 71, Folder PHSL097)